WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- And, uh, as you can see
from the locations,
the killer is working
primarily in the southern,
central and southeastern,
which makes sense
given the concentrations
of homeless in those districts.
Vics one and three
were killed at night,
two and four
had daylight t.o.d.s.
- Detective, what about
the missing man, Mr. Butler?
Is there any lead at all
on his whereabouts?
- No, sir.
We, uh--
We have teletypes with every
police agency in the mid-atlantic,
we're also running
daily morguehecks
in ten states
and the district,
but uh--
Nothing yet.
- Where are we
on a profile?
- I've arranged for our people
to travel to quantico today.
The bureau's been
very accommodating.
- I mean,
this is a strange one.
I've heard of people
going after street people,
but it's usually
adolescent sadism.
This sexual thing--
It is different.
We put it out on vicap,
and we have no hits anywhere
else in the country.
- I mean, I'm all for a little
kinky shit now and then,
but chewing
on a homeless fella?
- You seem to be well grounded
in the case file, detective.
What else do you need?
- Well, we've developed a rough
list of those adult males
who were briefly detained
by police near pier five
soon after the suspect
made his last call.
We'd like to put some of those
under surveillance.
They're not suspects,
but we wld consider them
persons of interest.
We've also developed
a rough list
of known adult white homosexual sex
offenders in these three districts.
And, as we cull that list,
we would--
We'd like to put some of those
under surveillance, too.
About a dozen men.
Less, actually.
We should be able to eliminate
many of our potentials
through retroactive
investigation.
Do you have your people?
- I've asked the chief of patrol
to detail sergeant ellis carver
from the western
homicide
for purposes of running
the surveillance element.
- Why not a man
from one of the districts
where the attacks
occurred?
- Well, I've worked
with carver
on prolonged investigations
in the past,
and his familiary with
surveillance tactics is relevant.
Also, I would be inclined to
trust his objective assessment
when choosing
surveillance teams.
Very good.
If that works for patrol,
it works for operations.
- What are we doing
to protect people?
- Patrol and tactical
are running extra cars
in all three districts
with special emphasis on posts
where the homeless
congregate.
We have ten undercovers,
dressed as vagrants,
working
staggered shifts.
- We're going to need
good undercover cars as well.
And I'm told that motor pool
expects nothing back
from dickman street
until--
- Whatever you need,
detective.
- Yes, Mr. Mayor, but we're
being told by public works--
- Go to avis
if you have to, hertz.
I don't give a shit.
People are disappearing.
Theye dying,
for crissake.
Just do what
you need to do.
The bad news, gentlemen,
is we're actually going to have
to catch this motherfucker.
The good news is that our mayor
finally needs a police department
more than he needs
a school system.
"A lie ain't a side of a story. It's just a lie."
- Terry Hanning.
Yo, can I help you?
I'm looking to work.
Here?
Yeah, you need anyone?
How old are you?
Eighteen.
A-ight, man,
i'm fifteen.
- I mean, yo, I can give you
a form to fill out,
but the manager, he ain't gonna
hire no one under seventeen.
Hey, yo.
You used to run
with the boy namond, right?
Yeah, I used to be
on them fayette corners.
- Oh yeah, man,
I remember you.
- Yeah, I just got tired,
ya know?
Shit got old.
So, I guess you need to bang
a while longer,
then come back,
see if we got something.
Then come back,
Why me?
Why not somebody
from a district
where they caught
one of your homeless cases?
Well, there's a hitch.
- This is some
fucked-up mcnulty shit.
I don't want
to get burned here.
And I don't want any
of my guys getting burned.
Look, here's the deal.
Command is throwing
more resources at me
than I can use
on my homeless stuff.
I got that covered.
But lester--he's got
a fresh line on marlo stanfield,
and he needs people
to run it down.
A fresh line, huh?
He's got a fuckin' wire up
is what you mean.
- No, no, there's no--
There's no wire--
- Who the fuck
are you kidding?
I handed him a fresh cell number
for stanfield not two weeks ago.
- Listen, I don't know anything
about any wire.
I'm just saying he's got
a new line on marlo,
and he needs people
to run it down.
Bosses stiff-armed him?
Jesus.
Guy drops all those
motherfuckers in the vacants.
Yeah.
- So you're throwing
people over to lester,
and paying for it
from your case, is that it?
O.t. Out the ass.
- What about
the paperwork?
I'll take care of that.
Althe run sheets,
office reports,
they come through me.
All your people got to do
is straight police work.
Daniels gave me a free hand
to pull people
from any district.
Just make sure you send me
people who work.
Mcnulty.
What about cars?
- Departmental account
at enterprise downtown.
Get what ya need.
- We delay fleet maintenance
for public works
over the next
three months.
We cut snow removal in half
and pray for global warming.
That's enough to avoid
any ugly cuts in school funding,
at least
for this quarter.
- And this funds police
operations fully, correct?
- They're back
to where they started
before we bled them out.
It's time anyway.
We ducked
the teacher layoffs,
and you got the fifteen points
on the third-grade m.s.a.s.
You can live with that.
But if we don't drop
the crime in this quarter,
and the next,
you are lnerable.
It's now or never.
- Besides, you're getting
traction in this homeless thing.
Governor was on y.p.r.
Yesterday,
and steiner laid him out
for the state cutbacks.
- Health care
for the homeless
have asked for city hall's
steps tomorrow night.
Candlelight vigil.
You said yes, right?
- Norman told 'em
they could do it
if I got a chance to say
a few choice words, yeah.
Speak of the devil.
- I just got off the phone
with the "post."
Reporter there wants
your comment
on a story he's workin
about dobey, down in p.g.,
looking to take you on
in the democratic primary.
What?
Dobey's getting in?
- Make matters worse,
upshaw's telling people
he might just throw in
with said county exec.
Shit, we might have a full-blown
p.g. Insurrection on our hands.
- Why the fuck
would they do that?
- Lots of pissed off
black folks down there.
Lot of grumblin' about always
a bridesmaid, never the bride.
- No way can dobey
take the statehouse.
All he's gonna do
is bloody us up
and make uspend money
we're gonna need in the general.
- When we went a-calling
in p.g. Last month,
who'd you see?
Steny.
Maloney, miller,
those guys.
White, white and white.
Not even a cup of coffee with
poor old congressman upshaw.
- I wasn't
snubbing the guy.
- Folks down there are tired
of being taken for granted.
- Fuck, I gotta kiss a ring,
don't i?
- More than a ring,
actually.
Unlimited o.t.
That's what I'm told.
- But you're sayin' we might not
be working the homeless cases.
Not all the time.
Major crimes
has a drug investigation
that may also need
surveillance work.
- Shit, who cares
what we work?
I need the money.
A-ight then.
You'll be
working out of homicide.
Report down there
to detective mcnulty.
Oh yeah--
Rented wheels
on the backlot.
Fuckin' a.
- Ah, man,
this is beautiful.
Oh, hell yeah.
- It's weird shit,
I gotta say.
Talkin' to a psychopath
like that.
- I interviewed
dick cheney once.
Whaddaya you think, gus?
Are we hyping this thing,
or is templeton
writing as it lays?
Police say it's real.
- An' those photographs
he got sent?
Hey, the guy's
fucking missing.
- So I guess now we're writing
homeless stories till december, huh?
Uh-huh.
Why till december?
- Pulitzer submissions
run the calendar year.
Anything a newspaper
cares about at christmas,
they give a fuck
about by new year's.
Homelessness
it is there, gents.
Hold on--
Fella down the lobby says
he wants to talk to an editor.
What kind of editor?
- The kind that worked on the
story about that homeless vet.
Scott's piece?
Sure they don't want
to talk to scott?
- Ys templeton won't
take his calls anymore,
so he walked over here
to talk to somebody else.
Tell him
someone's coming down.
That all he say?
- Just walked up
and said he got savino.
Said he gonna get
more of our muscle
if marlo don't come
to the street and step to him.
Good thing he didn't make me
from monk's apartment though.
I kept on lookin' away
from the motherfucker,
hopin' he ain't
remember me--
He was limpin' bad, too.
He had a crutch.
Wasn't lyin' about
savino, was he?
Everybody sayin'
omar's on this warpath.
Heard he got a stash house
last week.
Everybody's--
- Everybody need to
shut the fuck up.
Look, I'm just sayin',
if marlo was all that over
june bug callin' him a name,
so that y'all dropped june
and his whole family,
then what the fuck?
Omar out here callin' bitches
every damn day.
Fuck omar.
- What? What ya think we ain't
gonna catch this dicksucker?
This nigga gonna get got.
Y'all gonna tell marlo?
- We tell him,
we don't tell him.
- Man got enough
on his plate.
- Young'n's on some different
opinion shit there.
- I dunno.
If I was marlo--
Motherfucker, you ain't.
Raspberry?
Wild strawberry.
What?
Nothing, man.
- C'mon, man.
We gotta get across town.
- This bitch is gonna tell you
where there's construction.
It's gonna tell you left,
gonna tell you right.
Pretty much blow you
if you ask nice.
And look--
- Yo, you gotta play some old
school r&b shit on that, man.
- New car, o.t.
This fuckin' detail, man.
I hope we never catch
this goofy motherfucker.
- Hey, officers.
Lookey here.
You got two young bucks
'round the corner.
One in the white tee,
the other guy a throwback on.
One got the jump
his dip.
And the one with
a car tire, ya feel me?
'round the corner?
Fulton and lex.
A-ight.
Thanks, man.
Yeah.
Mr. Hanning?
It's an honor for me
to meet you, sir.
Who are you?
My name's gus haynes.
I edited the story
you're featured in.
- Then you're
a fucking liar.
- Omar.
It's omar, yo.
- Gotta giddy
up an' go, dawg.
get!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four.
Ya see there?
Omar know which one it is.
Look like all your muscle
done up and indisposed now.
So you might as well go ahead
and drop it out, ya feel me?
I'm a blast
to walk up in there now--
You workin'
a stanfield corner,
which means you workin'
for a straight up punk.
Ya feel me?
I'm out here in these streets
every day.
Me an' my lonesome.
An' where he at?
huh?
Yo, y'all put it
in his ear.
Marlo stanfield
is not a man for this town.
Ya dig?
Mmm-hmm--
Yeah--
Yeah, eight men,
four cars.
Ellis briefed 'em.
They know what's what.
No, they're just happy
for the o.t.
Look, don't worry, lester.
- Just sign the motherfucker
and shut the fuck up.
Gimme.
We ready?
'cause you gotta figure
an extra hour
to get 'round the capital
beltway this time of day.
You ever done
an f.b.i. Profile before?
Once.
How'd it go?
Oh, they take your file,
read you back some shit
you already know.
Then why do it?
So that we can saywe did.
- Need a pack of newport.
Soft pack.
And let me get one
of them, too--
Ahhhh!
Don't shoot!
- Lowenthal.
Where the fuck is he?
Um, he's, uh--
There you go, bunk.
- Hey. Request for
a d.n.a. Comparison.
case
Oh-six-h-two-seventy-one.
Latent trace
to obtained samples.
And it's a part of
the serial killer thing.
It's now a part
of that investigation.
Well, that's different.
If it's connected
to that investigation--
- It is.
It is, here.
It's in my notes.
- I never said
I was in a fire fight.
Not on that day.
- I'm sorry,
but you did.
- I told you the lead vehicle
took a hit from an elevated i.e.d.
Killed the fifty gunner,
and blew the hands
off the driver.
That's it.
That's enough, man.
Why you go and make
the rest of that shit up?
- I didn't make
anything up.
We sat there
having coffee--
Coffee--
- Having donuts
and coffee.
- And you said--
- What I say?
- Can I finish?
- I don't know.
I'm hearing about coffee
and donuts, I'm not hearing--
- Can I finish? If you're not going
to let me tell my side of the story--
- A lie ain't a side
of the story,
it's just a lie.
- I don't have to
listen to this--
- Okay--hey, scott,
let's just relax here.
Both you gentlemen, let's just
step back here, please?
Now, Mr. Hanning,
forgive me,
but do you drink much?
- You think I fucking sleep
under a bridge sober?
- Sometimes when I have a few--
And I do like to have a few--
I tend to be a little more
descriptive in the telling of a tale.
In fact--
- I know what it
is to tell a story.
I've told plenty
in my time.
But there's some things
that happen,
you don't ever
fuck with them.
Scott?
- I believe you,
mr. Hanning.
I believe
that you believe.
That you believe
you told me one thing.
But, sir, with all
due respect and gratitude
for you and the service
you gave to this country,
you didn't tell me
that thing.
You told me
something else.
I wrote what
mr. Hanning told me.
Mr. Hanning--
- I know you probably--
- What if one of the guys,
what if a marine
who was there--
He reads that shit
that you made up?
That's why
I come down here today.
What if one of the guys
sees that?
Man, get him
outta my face.
- Guy's just off.
Off in general.
Off his meds.
I dunno, but off.
A lot of them are,
you know.
- I mean, I hate to say it--
- Yeah, he puts on a good front.
We'll call the marines,
get a service record,
reach out to some people
in his unit,
find out what the fuck happened
that day outside of--
What was it?
Fallujah?
Yeah.
- Alright, if it went down
the way you said,
we'll let it be.
But if not, we'll chalk it up
as a misunderstanding.
But misunderstanding or no,
we will write a correction if
what we printed wasn't accurate.
- And we didn't
have coffee.
We had chocolate milk.
- You Miss what you had,
though?
- I still got too much dog in me
to be settled like that.
It wasn't cheryl.
It was me.
Thing is, is I found a connect
with the boy, you know?
That part of it
feels right to me.
Kids are great.
Yeah.
What about you an' beadie?
You were quiet there
for a time.
Yeah.
Bunk once told me
i'm no good for people.
Everyone around me,
he said.
Was he drunk?
- Yeah.
But still.
- Omar be dead.
I'm tellin' you.
Heard that before.
F'real.
You see him?
- Seen his dead ass
layin' right up in there.
Boy up on the corner say
he try to rob them koreans
and got kilt.
- You shoulda let me give him
the years, bunk.
He'da been better off.
Thanks for calling.
- Figured
you'd wanna see this,
you being so tight
with the mope.
Professional job here.
- Nah.
Thought so at first,
but the korean broad
we sent downtown
said he got done in by a short
little fella with a big gun.
Shit, walked in
an' lit his ass up.
How short?
The boy robbed him?
- Counterlady said the hoppers
all ran up in here
afterward for souvenirs.
Took his shotty
and his semiauto too.
Ran all through
his pockets.
Be my guest.
- Back on the hunt,
were you?
- Youngun say
he out here with no car,
walkin'
with a limp an' shit.
He gonna fall,
chris.
You gonna see.
Marlo need a meet.
For real?
- Leander,
where we at?
Still setting this up.
Why, did you catch
another one?
- Six-fifty-five
and thirty-four.
- Well,
we're not on anybody yet,
so we'll pick it up
in the morning.
- Alright.
Later.
Okay.
Doze, truck,
you're on monk metcalf.
Bobby, you and brian
are on chris partlow.
He usually rides
with snoop pearson,
but if they split,
karen and tony
will pick up on her.
Marcus, angela--
You're the backup unit
when we need one.
- You're gonna be stanfield?
- Yeah.
All their business
is face-to-face,
and they meet in the open
several times a day.
We're just trying to find
the pattern in the meets.
- Where do we pick
these guys up?
- Stanfield has every corner
between m.l.k. And monroe,
and they start shaping it up
around eleven or so, okay?
That's when the re-up orders
start coming in,
that's when you'll start to see
monk making the rounds.
Most mornings, marlo starts off
with a parley or two
on the playground
between mosher and lanvale.
Now, these guys
seem to be wholesaling, too.
Other dealers,
players--
Anyone who wants to get
with him gets him there, okay?
Chris and snoop
are usually with him.
And mcnulty's got you
covered for paperwork.
None of what we do here
is necessary for court,
so rest easy on that, alright?
So we stage here
tomorrow at nine.
No sign of him,
but I ain't on nothin' else
for as long as it take.
- You ain't heard?
Omar bagged up.
Shit, I thought y'all
was gonna tell me.
I just got the word myself
from monk.
- Who got him?
- Some young boy.
- Who?
- Ain't heard a name.
Don't even know
if there was a why.
Hopper wanna hear a pop,
see the damage, ya know?
Yeah--
That shit is gone.
We done
with this next resupply,
you an' me got some time
in a.c. Coming to us, don't we?
- Forensically, this guy
is all over the map.
Sexual to a point,
but inhibited.
Nocturnal on some,
diurnal on the others.
And the notion of targeting
the homeless, to begin with?
Well, we've only seen that
a couple times before,
but in those instances, it's
been someone within that cohort.
And they're not usually
carrying cell phones
and calling newspapers.
- You caught
a strange one here.
- Detectives,
hey, don't get up.
Arthur toland,
deputy director of the unit.
Just wanted to drop by
and make sure
we're progressing your case.
Yeah, yeah.
Great. Thanks.
- You might recognize
the director from television.
He's done all of them.
- You know
those news shows.
Always want a talking head
when a case comes up.
Greta van susteren,
nancy grace, chris matthews,
that fella with the big
forehead, whatshisname--
Larry king?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, what the hell.
It's a chance to get the word
out for the bureau.
And I sell some books.
"human hunters: the rise
of the american serial killer"?
They've used a lot of my stuff
on those c.s.i. Shows.
I've consulted for them.
You haven't heard--
So, how long you been doing
death investigations?
Eight years.
We don't see a lot of
serial stuff actually.
Drug murders.
A street robbery
every now and then.
- Three hundred or so
a year.
- Well, you've got
a serial case now,
so, I'll leave you to it.
Good hunting.
- Art was actually
lead investigator
on the unabomber thing.
- That was like
sixteen years, right?
Yeah.
- Yeah, then his brother
ratted him out?
- Homeless is in
at thirty inches.
It's good shit there.
No really.
There was a real
sense of place,
especially under
the hanover bridge
when the police came up
under there to give the warning.
Drama in small moments
like that.
- Truth is,
I had a tour guide.
Yeah?
- Yeah, fella I met
at a soup kitchen.
Volunteer there.
Ex-addict.
There's something
about this guy.
I mean, he's just--
I dunno, the more he talked,
the more I felt like
it was him I really
wanted to write about.
- Yeah?
- But he's not homeless.
And I don't have
any peg for him.
Shit, I don't know
what the story is.
Does he got a name?
Reginald cousins.
- Volunteers
at a soup kitchen.
What's he do for money?
- Sells the "baltimore sun"
every morning
out by light street.
- Well, shit not exactly
a growth industry, huh?
- He lives
in his sister's basement.
She'll take a plate down
to him every now and then,
but she won't let him
come up the stairs.
- Spend some time
with him.
- What about
the neighborhoods beat?
The homeless coverage?
You're covered.
Take a couple weeks,
see what you see.
A-ight?
- Late entries
from the copshop.
Two dead in
a charles county housefire,
and a homicide
from the city.
- Ettlin,
what do we got room for?
- We're shy one brief
in the metro digest.
Four paragraphs'll fill.
What's the homicide?
- The 34-year-old
black male
shot dead
in west baltimore grocery.
Juvenile suspect
is being sought.
Write up the fire.
Scratch the murder.
We don't have room.
- So what we conclude
from a behavioral analysis
of the known forensics
is the following:
the suspect is likely
a white male,
in his late twenties
to late thirties.
He likely is not
a college graduate,
but feels
nonetheless superior
to those with
advanced education,
and he is likely employed
in a bureaucratic entity,
possibly civil service
or quasi-public service,
from which
heeels alienated.
He has a problem
with authority
and a deep-seated resentment
of those who he feels
have impeded his progress
professionally.
The minimized sexual activity
suggests
that this is not a primary
motive for the killings.
In fact, the bite marks
in the last found victim--
Lacking the d.n.a. Of saliva--
Indicate to us
possible post-mortem staging.
The suspect has trouble
with lasting relationships
and is possibly
a high-functioning alcoholic,
with alcohol being utilized
as a trigger
in the commission
of these crimes.
His resentment
of the homeless
may stem from
a personal relationship
with someone
who is in that cohort,
or his victimization
of vagrants
might merely present
an opportunity for him
to assert his superiority
and intellectual prowess.
If you get more,
fax it down,
and we can
update the profile.
Thanks for everything.
Thanks.
So, what do you think?
They're in the ballpark.
- Look, congressman,
i'll do whatever it takes
to make things right
between us,
but running dobey in the primary
is only gonna hurt everybody.
You mean hurt you.
- All due respect,
i'm the only viable candidate
to beat that republican prick,
and I know you know that.
And, at the end of the day,
isn't that what it's all about?
Do not waste your breath
tellin' me what I already know
about our tax-cutting,
dump-it-on-the-counties,
ass-kiss-every-business-interest governor.
P.g. County has
a hundred murders a year,
school system held together
with spit and glue,
and worse rush-hour trafficthan atlanta.
And the man in annapolis
wouldn't piss on us
if we were on fire.
- Don't hold back,
congressman.
- I'm tired of these
fuckin' republicans.
- Look, I fucked up
not coming to see you earlier.
But between the votes
I can pull outta baltimore,
montgomery and your county,
I am gonna take the statehouse.
And then the frustration
that you feel is gonna end.
I know you've heard this before
from every other sonofabitch,
but congressman,
I give you my word.
- You know,
you're right.
I have heard that before.
You wanna keep p.g. County
in your camp,
it's gonna cost you
a lot more than your word.
Fuck.
You rang?
Funny case you got here.
Your victim
had an address.
A home.
Paid rent,
so we assume,
maybe even a mortgage.
But not homeless,
in any case.
No strangulation,
no red ribbon--
Christopher partlow.
A lesser man
might get pissy
because you jumped the line,
bunk.
me?
I remember partlow's name
from all those cases last year.
Congrats.
Yeah.
- But don't fuck with me
like this again.
Yeah. Yeah.
- He lied on his mortgage
application, huh?
You know, we have a name
for that over here.
- Yeah, the headshot.
I know.
- On a mortgage charge,
he's certain to plead out.
- Billy doesn't plead
his clients.
- Then he's looking
at a lot of years.
A federal jury
is a very different animal
than what they see
on calvert street.
- I tried
to tell them that--
---Yeah, but mister bond
wanted to try is himself,
see if he couldn't grandstand
his way to city hall.
Well, you have the headshot,
detective.
But no gun with which
to fire it.
We can't take this case.
It's all on paper.
- You had canceled checks.
You had bank accounts.
You had his bag man
on the stand.
We had a city jury.
- You know, we've been gathering
string on clay davis
for six years,
detective.
Six years, we've had a file open
on that shakedown artist.
And now, after you
city sons of bitches
have managed, in a single week,
to transform clay fucking davis
into martin luther king, jr.,
you now come to me with this--
Which you had in your
back pocket all along--
Looking for the federal jury
of mostly white faces
to remedy the problem?
Well, I'm sorry.
Thank you.
What's this?
- From the pocket
of a dead stick-up boy.
Omar little.
Omar? Dead?
- You stop readin'
the twenty-fours?
Killed yesterday
at a grocery.
Slow to the draw,
he was.
No shit.
- One to the back
of the head.
Norris and crutchfield
caught it.
They're looking
for a juvenile.
He was hunting
stanfield and crew.
And this was on him?
yep.
Thought of you and lester
when I saw it.
Payback for you
getting me back some great lab.
Positive d.n.a.
On chris partlow.
An alley beating, not one
of the ones in the vacants.
Motherfucker.
You have all kinds
of news today, don't you?
- Yeah, going for a warrant
right now.
- Hey, can you wait
to serve it?
We're right at the edge,
bunk.
How long?
'cause this is an honest
fuckin' murder prosecution here.
I'll talk to lester.
Congrats.
- Yeah.
No shuckin', no jivin'.
Just good ol'
police work.
How about that, jimmy?
Hey, without my bullshit,
you're still
waiting on lab work.
- Listen, jimmy, the conaway
shooting from westport?
The transvestite?
I go to vicap, there's
another one just like it--
Look--down in carolina,
four months ago.
For a road car
and two nights in a hotel,
I can put this down.
- What are you
talking about?
Yours is a 9 mm,
this one's a 32.
Yours was a bar pick-up,
this one's a home invasion--
- Still worth
checking out.
- I don't see it.
Sorry.
- You're gonna make me
spit it out, aren't you--
You ever played
hilton head?
I get a call from my
brother-in-law a few days ago.
He managed to swing
a tee-time for this weekend.
Jimmy,
i'm going, goddammit.
The fuck do I care? Go.
- You know, this is some real
cute shit you're pulling here.
Taking the detail money
and doling it around
ke a priest passing wafers.
Now, I don't know
exactly what you're up to,
but I know this: if someone
picked up a phone around here,
your shit is
critically fucked.
Two nights
and a road car.
- Leander, I'm showing ten-fifty-five
and thirty-four from marlo's phone.
Anybody on the move?
- I got him coming eastbound
on baltimore street at calhoun.
Who's on monk?
Wait one.
Twenty-three-oh-six
to twenty-three-eleven.
Where you at, man?
Twenty-three-eleven.
Southbound m.l.k.
Approaching route forty.
That's the meet, lester.
Monk and marlo
on the westside.
We on it.
- Corner of argyle
and dolphin.
Monk and marlo,
as expected.
- Now I got four-forty and
thirty-five coming into marlo's phone.
- Yeah, he's scoping
that, lester.
- We know it ain't
monk callin'.
- Twenty-three-oh-six
to twenty-three-twelve.
Twenty-three twelve.
Who do you have eyes on?
Both my subjects.
- They go to
their cell phones?
Negative.
They on the move?
Twenty-three-fourteen.
- We got nothing moving either.
- No one elscalling or moving.
- Means we got somebody else
on this network
we don't yet know.
Oh, boy.
- Hey, man.
Let me give you a hand.
Alright, you ready?
ah.
- I don't have no money
in the moment,
but I'll be going down
to the scales in a hour or two.
You help me out,
i'll go ten for your trouble.
Got a rag
for that behind you.
Junk!
Junkman!
Junk! Junk!
Junkman! Junk!
- Where the fuck
are you going?
- Oh, uh, I gotta
see lester about--
What's all that?
- Parole info on known sex
offenders for five zip codes.
I've also got background
info on my desk
for everyone we picked up
at pier five with a cell phone.
- You're actually gonna--
- Compare the f.b.i. Profile
with every person of interest
I can find.
Hell yeah,
somebody's gotta.
- Come here.
- The fuck are you doin'?
Come here.
- Maurice dobey?
For governor?
Of my state?
Sheet.
That's some cynical politics,
right there.
Playin' like you gonna
run a man you know can't win
to scare people
into payin' off.
- Dobey could
bloody you up, tommy.
In baltimore
and p.g. Both.
- Playin' that race card.
Shameful.
- What does upshaw want
to stay out of the race?
Tomuch.
Are you going to pay?
- Well, let's just say
i'm in negotiations.
- Well, I'll do everything
I can to make sure
this insurrection
doesn't spread into the city.
- Wonderful! And how much
is the loyal support
of the eastside democratic
coalition going to cost me?
- Only an endorsement,
given that this man right here
is still standing,
I don't believe that rupert bond
is going to find his way
into this office.
Do you?
And for my endorsement,
you will return the favor
and ignore our friends
in prince george's.
And the loyalty
of the westside
is going to cost me
what exactly?
Oh, nothin' big.
You got three seats comin' open
on the liquor board.
You get one seat.
Two, and you have me out there
raising money for you in the primary.
Sold. And clay,
it scares me to think of the damage
you could do with two votes on the liquor board.
It ain't right.
No... It just is.
No, I mean, you can't do this.
We're doing it. Whatever
they give us to work the bullshit,
I throw it to lester. Or crutchfield,
or norris. Anyone else who has a case ***
it was bad enough I wasted your day
yesterday going to quantico,
I can't stand to see you wasting
any more time on this,
you should be back working
your home invasion.
- Jimmy, you can't do this.
- A couple days more.
Lester gets his best shot at marlo,
after that
we'll never hear
from the *** killer again.
Bosses will lose interest,
i'll pretend to run out of little more string.
And then it goes right back to the adman office.
No harm, no foul.
Whatever you need, kima...
To work your triple,
or any case that matters to you.
Manpower, o.t., labwork, cars...
Just let me know.
I gotta go.
Wake up!
Hey, bug! Up here.
Hold, boy.
I'll get you that 10 tomorrow.
And if you're looking for work,
I got work needs lifting.
You know the stable on Booth Street?
Be there before 9.
Dang, dukie ***
i'm showing 5:15 and 34 seconds.
I'm up park heights,
but I lost him just past the park.
M.t.a. Bus
clipped a curb
and it knocked down
a utility pole.
By the time I detoured,
he slipped me good.
Well, let me know.
Big news.
Bunk has a murder warrant
on chris partlow.
The hell you say.
- Not one
from the vacants.
D.n.a. Match
on an alley beating.
He lets this go now,
these guys are gonna
go to ground.
We're right at the edge
of something here.
- He's giving us
a couple of days.
He owes me.
I expedited his lab work
for it.
Oh, and omar little?
Stickup-boy?
What about him?
- Caught one in a korean joint
over westside.
Bunk pulled that out
of his pocket.
Mean anything
at all to us?
- Look's like he was
after marlo's crew.
Cheese.
Cheese wagstaff?
In addition
to their corners,
these guys are wholesaling
all over town at this point,
so I figured cheese
was just one of many.
- Note reads like omar
had him under marlo'wing.
A lieutenant, at least.
Anyway,
I gotta go,
do more pretending
for the rest of the city.
Oh, by the way,
i--I told greggs.
- Oh, mcnulty.
How many more people--
- She was about to jump into the
serial murders with both feet.
I couldn't stand
to spin her like that--
How'd she take it?
- Twenty-three-oh-six to
any twenty-three sequence.
Trying to reconnect
with my subject.
- Anyone near northwest
who can assist?
- Twenty-three-fifteen
to twenty-three-oh-six.
I'm in the twenty-eight
hundred block
edgecombe circle south,
sitting on the female subject.
Maybe that's the other end
of your meet.
Edgecombe circle?
Where's that, twenty?
It runs off pall mall.
Where's pall mall?
I'm not too good up
in the northwest.
It's between pimlico--
- Never mind,
I got a map book.
Okay,
see what we got here.
Map thirty-four,
grid e-three.
Thirty-fr, e-three,
thirty-four, e-three--
Three--
Whaddya got?
- Lester,
what'd that last clock show?
- And these people that I
share the stage with tonight
are here as representatives
of the hundreds,
no, the thousands of citizens
without shelter,
without protection,
in this city tonight.
Why does this have to be?
Certainly,
the last seven years
have not brought the same levels
of federal commitment
to american cities as from
previous administrations.
And certaiy, our governor
has in the last year
placed severe restrictions on whatever
stopgap state programs were in place.
And what little remained
of our so-called safety net
was simply shredded,
and more and more
of our fellow citizens
found themselves living life
at the broken edges,
in the street.
Well, I say that this is
not on tragic,
it is unforgivable!
And I am here to say
that no longer can these people
with whom I share this stage
tonight be invisible,
just, just, just as all of those
without shelter in this city,
in this country, can
no longer be invisible to us.
And it is regrettable
that it has taken the actions
of a remorseless predator
to make us reflect.
But we in baltimore
have been tested,
and we have been taught
that all of our citizens
deserve the full protection
of the law,
and the full support
of the community.
And we are saying
to this senseless killer,
and to all the other ills
that prey on those
without shelter
in our city--
Not tonight
can you prey on them.
And not tomorrow.
Not any longer.
We will protect you!
Thank you.
- She asked you keep
that one stirred.
- Hey, you were
on my thing, right?
I guess I owe you
a drink on that.
What's your poison?
- I'm okay, senator,
thank you very much.
Obonda, huh?
That's a good one.
You know, that was mostly my
evidence you beat back there, right?
You think you
could do that again?
Excuse me?
- 'Cept this time,
the jury's a federal one.
Say, nine white,
three black.
- Time for you
to tip on out, detective.
- Bank records
on that mortgage application
you made on the calvert county
property years back.
Now, why don't you
take that back to billy murphy?
Ask your attorney
what you're exposed to.
At this point, this is just between
us two gentlemen here, senator.
And no one else
till I make it so.
What?
You tryin' to sell
a case back to me?
Motherfucker,
if you don't get--
- I don't get paid
like that.
I get paid when
I come bacup in here
a couple nights time
with questions.
And you, sir,
have answers.
Or my next call will be
to the u.s. Attorney's office,
and we will go again.
But for real.
You can keep tt copy.
Ma'am.
You can keep that copy.
- Just to let you know,
before the fireworks start,
i'm spiking this lede
and I'll play it straight.
But you got back?
As best I can.
Scott!
I'm spiking your lede.
I'm not running a story
about a public gathering--
A candlelight vigil
at city hall, in fact--
Where the lede anecdote and quote
is from an unnamed homeless woman.
- She doesn't want to be
known as homeless.
I explained that.
- Scott, there were hundreds of
homeless down there tonight--
People who voluntarily
attended this event.
And I'm gonna guess
that any number of them
would've let you put
their names in the paper.
- But her story is great.
Look at that quote--
It's a perfect quote.
Best quote
I could ever ask for.
Jesus christ.
To hell with you
if you think I made it up.
- We have a standard
that we follow here.
And I'm gonna follow it.
Here it comes, gus.
yep.
- Gus, you're retopping
scott's vigil copy?
I am.
But I thought--
- Anonymous attribution
in a public setting.
There's no need for it.
Gus, let's discuss this.
- Actually,
I did discuss it.
I discussed it
with the metro editor,
and he agrees.
Now, the story's
on the copy desk,
and as a line editor
working this story,
I feel I've done my job.
Now, you as the m.e.,
if you want to go another way,
you pull the story back
and re-edit.
But we have a sourcing
policy here,
and I knowt,
and I do not feel comfortable
bending the rules
in this instance.
G'night.
Yeah?
- Mcnulty,
it's christeson.
Listen,
my case is down an'
I wanted
to thank you.
I couldn't have done it
otherwise.
No problem.
Hey. It went great.
Kids asleep?
- Yeah, but they saw you
on w.b.a.l.
Anna said your hair
looked funny.
- Well, just so long as
she was impressed.
Cnn was there.
I wonder if they'll cycle
any coverage through tonight.
- A good day
for hizzoner, huh?
I dunno.
Nerese shook me down
for a mayoral endorsement,
and clay davis,
back from the grave,
took a couple
liquor board seats.
Just so as they won't join
in upshaw's little warparty
down in prince george's.
- You're gonna endorse
nerese?
You told me
you prefer bond.
- I do,
but this thing with upshaw--
Shit, I might even
have to give him a bump
just to calm him down.
- God.
What's he asking?
There--look.
What's upshaw asking?
- Half of any extra school
or anti-crime money
I get outta the legislature
for baltimore
would go to p.g. County.
- You take that deal
and baltimore's out
half of what you want to bring
back to the city schools.
- Yeah, but if I don't win, jen,
I bring back exactly nothing.
Look.
- And we are saying
to this senseless killer,
and to all the other ills--
- Go on.
Straight to bed.
Hey, kiddo.
Hey, mcnulty.
Where'd you go to?
- None of your business
really, jimmy.
Next time,
i'm not going anywhere.
Next time, you're gonna
be out on your ass,
because that's
my fucking house.
That's police work, son.
- I pull the a.d.c. Book
to find a location,
and I'm on the same page number
as the second hand.
And I remember
wead a lotta clocks
with thirty-four seconds.
- That's a page
from west baltimore.
Right.
Now, the second hand
is always the map page.
Longitude, a-through-k,
is the hour,
and for the latitude, they go
by five-minute intervals.
Now they know
the meeting spot in advance,
and they code it
by the grid square.
But if the clock
has nothing to do with time,
how do they know
when to meet?
- Everything's less than
a half hour of driving,
even in traffic.
My guess is
that the standing logic
is that they meet
within an hour or so.
You know what else
makes sense?
This clock face when no one
was on the move?
The times are all
at thirty-five seconds.
And that's the page
for east bawlmer.
Cheese.
Cheese wagstaff?
- Marlo's wholesaling
on the westside through monk,
and on the eastside
with cheese.
He's got the whole
goddamn city.
- How do we know
it's cheese?
oh--
You, too, huh?
You all
are good with this?
Kima--
Not me.
All the guysat the bar, jimmy?
All the girls?
They don't show up
at your wake.
Not because
they don't like you
but because they never
knew your last name.
A month later, someone tells 'em
"oh, jimmy died."
"jimmy who?"
"jimmy the cop."
"ohh," they say.
"him."
And all the people
on the job,
all the people you spent all
those hours in the radio car with,
the guys with their feet up
on their desk telling stories,
who shorted you
on the food runs,
who signed your
overtime slips.
In the end, they're not
gonna be there either.
Family.
That's it.
And if you're lucky,
one or two friends
who are the same as family.
That's all
the best of us get.
Everything else is just--
- There is no
serial killer.
There are no murders.
I made it all up.
They were--they were
shutting us down.
They were--
They were just--
It's hard to explain.
I don't even know
where the anger comes from.
I don't know
how to make it stop.
They fucking task me,
they do.
We took the money from
the bullshit investigation,
and we routed it
to lester.
Now he's got the cake
to take down marlo stanfield.
And now
that I've done all this--
Now that I've
watched myself do it,
I can't even stand to--
Lester says he's close.
Time will pass,
and I'll be able
to shut this thing down.
If you don't go to jail.
You had no fucking right.
- I know.
- This is my life, too.
You start to tell the story;
you think you're the hero.
And then, when you get done
talking, you--
from thewire-france.com
for wikisubtitles.net